Érase una vez
en una tierra cierta
donde vivía una jovencita que era muy habladora,
y le daba muchas vueltas a la imaginación.
Y esta jovencita
estaba enamorada con el castillo de la cima de la montaña.
Empty / Full
Qué bonito.
The young girl dreams.
NOTICE
Rest Rate: 5,000 yen
Stay Rate: 7,000 yen
"¡Algún día, yo también iré al baile del castillo
con un príncipe azul!"
¡¿Papi?!
¡Mami! ¡Mami!
Thank you for your hard work
Anda, hola.
¡Estoy en casa! ¡Mami, adivina qué, adivina qué!
¡Acabo de descubrir un gran secreto!  ¡Toma, un poquito de huevo frito!
Qué rico...
Sweet!
Desde luego, Jun, qué charlatana eres.
Espera un momentito.
I'm going to finish making
Daddy's late-night snack now.
¡Sí! ¡Papi acaba de salir del castillo!
¿Castillo? ¡Sí! ¡El de la montaña!
¿Ves? ¡Papi es un príncipe!
Pero la princesa no eras tú...
¿Te has perdido el baile porque estabas cocinando, mami?
Espera, podrías ser una bruja, ¿a lo mejor?
Pero ¡apuesto a que tú eres una bruja buena!
Las brujas malas son más...
Jun...
no debes decir nada más.
¿Por qué no?
No debes contarle a nadie esto.
Jamás vuelvas a hablar sobre eso.
¿Jamás?
Muy bien, ese era la última.
Por favor, firme aquí.
Ah, claro.
Y así
el príncipe con la prominente barriga
fue desterrado de su casa por la bruja buena
y envió a la princesa en contra de su voluntad.
Papi...
Oye, ¿adónde vas?
Eh... Estaré en el coche.
Vale. Muchas gracias.
Oye...
¡S-Si te has peleado con mami, te ayudaré a hacer las paces!
Así papi, puedes quedarte aquí, como siempre...
Jun.
Desde luego, qué charlatana eres.
Todo esto es culpa tuya, ¿no lo ves?
Thank you for waiting.
All right, I'll lead the way.
Gracias.
Alguien, mi príncipe...
por favor, ven y rescátame en estos instantes.
¡Hola! Soy tu príncipe.
¿Por qué eres un huevo y no un príncipe?
Pero ¡yo soy un príncipe! ¿Ves?
Si escondo esto... ¿ves?
¡Mi príncipe no esconde cosas como tú, y tampoco huele a pedo!
¡Ay, señor, qué boquita más sucia!
Desde luego, qué charlatana eres.
¿Una charlatana? ¿Hasta un huevo me llama así?
Because you're such a chatterbox,
you'll be facing turmoil
and drama in the life ahead of you.
Un tipo de charlatana que son víctimas de los sospechosos vendedores de teléfono.
¡Un tipo de charlatana que se le ajusta con zapatos de cemento y los tiran al mar!
¿Al mar?
Así es. Escucha.
Si no quieres llevar ese tipo de vida, tienes que medir tus palabras.
¿Medir?
Sí.
Si puedes hundir tus palabras en el mar,
nunca podrás ser estafada por un vendedor de teléfonos.
¡Tendrás la oportunidad de conocer a un príncipe de verdad e irás a un castillo de verdad!
¿Sí?
P-Pero ¿qué pasa si no puedo dejar de hablar?
Entonces tu príncipe, tu castillo... Todo se convertirá en humo.
¿En humo?
De verdad, de verdad de la buena, se convertirán en humo.
La yema y las claras.
¡Bátelas juntas como un plato de huevos revueltos!
¡No!
Pero ¿qué debería hacer? No puedo medir...
Bien.
Para curarte de ser tan charlatana,
voy a ponerte una cremallera en la boca.
Ziiiiiiiiip...
¿Un huevo?
¡Eh! ¡Chiquillo! ¡Chiquillo!
¡Recógelos! ¡Recógelos!
¿Palabras?
Sí, aquí. Oh, gracias.
A este dios en particular le gusta hablar.
Habla con huevos y los llena con todo tipo de palabras.
¿Cualquier palabra?
¡Así es!
Como: "quiero dormir con una bombón de mujer" o "quiero partirle la cara a ese idiota". ¡Cualquier cosa!
Y entonces, los cuelgas aquí y será como una ofrenda.
¿Y qué pasa si haces eso?
Bueno, ¡supongo que debe de haber algún tipo de beneficio!
Vague, much?
¡Nas! ¡Buenos días!
¿Te preparas para la clase? Todavía no.
Entonces ¿qué? ¿Qué acabaste haciendo?
Of course, I whacked his ass
with my bat!
¡Estos uniformes son monísimos!
A ver, déjame ver.
Sí, el equilibrio del color es genial.
Como este logo de aquí...
Oh, sí, sí. Supongo que teniendo un logo estupendo los une a todos juntos.
¡Nas días, Taku!
Llegas tarde, ¿eh?
Me he entretenido. Oye, pues no está mal.
¡Iwaki, te has superado!
¿Sí?
Ah, ¡buenos días, Taku!
¡Bien! ¿Qué tal si nos sentamos?
Veamos...
Nuestro problema sin resolver: el Comité de Compromiso Comunitario.
We've reached our time limit on that.
We're gonna decide on it now!
En primer lugar, ¿por qué tenemos que hacerlo?
Solo uno por cada curso, ¿no?
Yo ya lo hice cuando íbamos a primero, ¿sabes?
Bueno, bueno, olvidemos los pequeños detalles.
¡Cualquier persona que esté interesada que lo diga en los próximos cinco segundos!
¡Qué lata! ¿Qué pasa? Cinco, cuatro, tres, dos...
Cinco, cuatro, tres, dos...
uno, cero. ¡Vale, se acabó el tiempo!
Me lo suponía. ¡Por lo tanto...
ya he elegido a nuestro comité!
Veamos...
Takumi Sakagami.
Jun Naruse.
Daiki Tasaki.
Natsuki Nito.
Así que de todos modos,
¡cuento con vosotros!
¿Tú entiendes algo, Natsuki?
No lo sé. ¿Qué está pasando?
Como ha dicho... Estás de coña.
Shimaccho picked this year's
Outreach Committee himself.
Ni de coña voy a hacer esto.
Dai, tío.
¿No debería estar asignando esto a los marginados sociales?
Well, no.
I'm a teacher of extreme integrity,
so I don't play favorites like that.
Después de todo, el tiempo se reparte en partes iguales entre todos nosotros.
Incluso las lombrices de tierra, los grillos. ¿Adónde quiere ir a parar?
Simplemente, hazlo.
Es una orden.
Mira tú...
¿qué estás diciendo?
¡Dai! ¡Tío!
Yo...
no quiero...
¿Naruse ha hablado?
¡Tío, puede hablar!
estar en el comité...
Oye, Naruse.
¡Te has pasado tres pueblos, Shimaccho! ¡Pobrecilla!
¿Qué vamos a hacer?
¡Sakazaki, tío! ¿Sakazaki?
Es Sakagami.
Sorry, I was close, though.
Not that close.
De todas modos, el resto te lo dejo a ti.
- That was pretty wild earlier, huh?
- Right?
DTM Research Club
¡Corta el rollo, Aizawa! Estás usando a Miss Mint para una canción guarra.
¿De qué estás hablando?
Isezaki-cho Blues es un clásico, tío.
¿Vas a pelear contra el gran Mina Aoe?
¿Verdad, Taku?
Pareces cansado, Taku.
Deberías escaquearte del Comité de Compromiso Comunitario.
No one's gonna show up
but the old folks from the neighborhood.
Claro, como no a ti no te ha tocado...
¡No es nuestro problema!
But that selection of his.
Se fue por la pasión de la juventud. ¡La agonía de la adolescencia!
¡Una juventud apática, encerrado en su propia cascara!
Una estrella aguafiestas del instituto de béisbol con sueños rotos, y una chica eternamente muda.
Oye, yo nunca había oído la voz de Naruse hasta hoy.
Y también una chica recta que siempre parece estar a cargo.
¡Desde el punto de vista de las personalidades, eso es este, sur, oeste y norte!
Ron!
Shousuushi! (Little Four Happiness)
¡Lo he conseguido! ¿En serio?
Voy a ir a quejarme a Shimaccho.
¡Mierda!  ¡Te está bien empleado, Aizawa!
Ahora que lo pienso...
También ha sido la primera vez que he oído su voz.
¡Mía!
Dale.
¡Eh! ¡No puedo oírte, gandul!
Hay que joderse con Shimaccho. ¿Con quién se cree que está tratando?
Pero al estar en el comité con Natsuki podríais acercaremos más.
¿Qué estás suponiendo?
El capitán del equipo de animadores siempre es la estrella de las citas. ¡Es como una tradición!
Yamaji es nuestro lanzador estrella ahora, ¿recuerdas?
A-Ah...
Fallo mío.
¡Mishima!
Te están llamando.
Bueno... ¡Voy!
Ve a la reunión, ¿vale?
Es un poquito triste, ¿no?
¿Eh? ¿El equipo de béisbol?
Well, since their dreams of the Nationals
weren't all that far-fetched.
¡Todo el mundo estaba tan entusiasmado gracias a Daiki!
Su objetivo era superar la tercera ronda de las preliminares del torneo de verano.
And thanks to their ace,
who'd flourished into an elite talent,
they could feel as if they were
within striking distance of the Nationals!
Fall Regional Baseball Championships Rising Star, Daiki Tasaki (15) Collects
the Most Strikeouts in the Tournament
¡Era un sueño tan claro!
Summer Nationals Ageha High Fails to Become
Best 4
¿Quién se iba a imaginar que se lastimaría el codo?
Hey, don't be like that.
Ikkun will be devastated.
ITSUKI MISHIMA
"IKKUN"
¡No, no! ¡Ikkun no debería sentir pena! ¡Si no yo!
All that practice
for the tournament went to waste.
¿Qué estáis haciendo? ¡Descansad!
¡Lo siento! ¡Ahora vamos!
Music Room
Perdone.
He oído que debería estar aquí.
Voy a entrar.
¿Qué es esto?
Es como si fuera si propia casa.
¿Otra vez los huevos?
¿Qué pasa? ¿Hoy es el Día del Huevo?
Funciona, ¿eh?
Huevos, huevos
déjame ofrecer los huevos.
Beautiful words
Estas palabras,
déjame ofrecerlas
a los huevos.
¿Tengo invitados?
¿Naruse? ¿Qué estás haciendo aquí?
¡Naruse! ¿Ya te vas?
Vaya.
Is this an appeal?
¡Bien por ella!
Si puede hablar, debería decírselo a su cara.
Sí, bueno.
Estoy por la misma razón, por cierto.
¿Eh?
There's no way we can pull it off
with those members.
Aparte de Nito...
Entonces, dime quiénes podrían llevarlo adelante.
Offer up some human sacrifices,
and I'll be happy to switch you out.
You're too nice!
Pero esa naturaleza podría ser tu pérdida.
And who's the cause of it?
Por cierto, me ha gustado mucho.
La canción que tocabas.
That was just something random.
Around the World, ¿verdad?
Es una antigua película. Me sorprende que la conocieras.
Bueno...
solía estar con alguien que iba a los musicales.
¡Esa podría ser la razón!
¡Un musical!
¡Sería perfecto para el evento del Compromiso Comunitario!
¿A qué viene eso?
Soy un profesor de música.
Recitaciones y coros, año tras año.
No lo hacen por mí.
They're more than enough for us.
¡Oye, yo no soy de los que se rinden tan fácilmente!
Lo ha visto.
Ha visto dentro de mi corazón.
Estoy en casa.
Hola.
Ese coche...
¿Qué estás haciendo?
Sí, creo que estos frenos no tienen arreglo.
Usa la mía.
Pero ¿no la necesitas para ir a la escuela?
No, puedo ir andando.
A ti te hace falta para ir al hospital, ¿no, abuelo?
Estoy en...
Yes, you can reevaluate this one every year,
so that should set your mind at ease.
Cuando Dios nos tenga en su gloria, ¿cómo se pagará el dinero?
Tampoco necesita preocuparse por eso.
Por ejemplo, cuando su niet..
Anda, ¡hola, Takkun!
Hola.
¿Este es su nieto?
Sí.
He visto que su nieto va también a Ageha.
Querida, ¿su hija va también ahí, señorita Naruse?
S-Sí...
¿La conoces? ¿A la señorita Naruse?
¿Naruse? Disculpe...
¿Te refieres a Jun Naruse?
Sí.
¿La conoces?
No, solo por su nombre.
A-Ah, ¿sí?
Ah, por cierto, bajo el plan que acabo de explicar, hay otra ventaja...
Aquí está. Oh, sí.
Si añade esta función,
recibirá esta ventaja.
All right, I'll be leaving now.
¡Está criando a su hija sola! Es admirable.
Oh, está bueno.
Ms. Naruse brought those over.
Cream red-bean pancake.
She's a cheerful little chatterbox, isn't she?
Her mother says she's always on the phone
with her friends, so their phone bill's astronomical!
Uh, no...
¿Hablas de cosas privadas de esa forma?
¡Después de todo, estamos poniendo nuestras vidas en sus manos!
Oh, no, querido. ¡Tres es demasiado!
Entonces, ¿no tiene padre?
Estoy seguro de que todos habéis escuchado esto al menos una vez.
Over The Rainbow.
Es un gran éxito de la película El Mago de Oz.
Lo sé. El camino de las baldosas amarillas, ¿verdad?
Así es. Arrastrada a una tierra fantástica, la heroína, Dorothy...
hace todo lo posible para poder volver a su casa en Kansas. Es una historia sencilla.
En los musicales, transmites tus emociones a través de las canciones y cantas y bailas con ellas.
Esto hace que sea muy fácil comunicarse, incluso los sentimientos son demasiados tímidos para expresarse normalmente.
¡Así que de todos modos, vamos a ver la peli juntos hoy!
Nah, no existe.
La palabra "musical" no está en el diccionario Aizawa.
It kind of sends chills
down your spine, doesn't it?
Right, right.
They could just say the lines...
but then they burst into song.
That's what I don't get.
Yeah, but like Shimaccho said,
maybe singing the lines
helps get your feelings across better.
¡Acabas de soltar una perla, Taku!
¡Shimaccho te ha envenedado!
Anda ya.
Ya veo. Así que Tasaki no se ha presentado.
Le recordé que viniera, pero...
Qué más da.
Me dijo que nos dejaba todo esto a nosotros.
Decidamos sin él.
Eso no es bueno...
¡Se supone que esta es nuestra histórica primera reunión del comité!
Well, as far as decision-making goes,
it's not like we have that many choices.
¿Quizá deberíamos ir solo con coro o recitaciones?
¿Qué? Pero ¡eso sería lo mismo, lo mismo de siempre!
Pero...
Pero ¿no es eso lo que la gente espera del evento del Compromiso Comunitario?
As far as mingling with the community goes,
no one really shows up
but the elderly who live nearby.
The elderly have pretty modern taste, you know!
Not making any changes, just sticking with
the status quo. How boring is that?
So? What are you getting at?
You know as well as I do!
You mean what we did in class today.
Class?
What do you say, Naruse?
A musical?
Mu...
Naruse? Are you all right?
A musical?
What are we gonna do?
I bet everyone's
gonna vote against it.
Let's not worry
about that now.
I guess not.
Then tomorrow in homeroom,
let's let everyone–
Jeez, that Tasaki's
such a pain in the butt!
Where does he get off,
bossing us around?
He's a piece of junk who blew out his elbow
just when we needed him.
Showing up everyday just to rip into us.
Yamaji, you set him straight!
Not me. Just ignore him.
- Yeah, but...
- Hey!
We're gonna head out to do some laps now!
Right!
I don't like that kind of thing.
If they have something to say,
they should just speak up.
Uh, I've got practice.
So I'll be going on ahead!
Okay.
Uh, I'm heading home now.
See you.
What's up with her?
Listen...
Naruse, by any chance,
do you actually want to do a musical?
What?
Are you peeking
into my heart?
"Are you...?"
What's this?
Don't pretend you don't–
Naruse?
Are you okay?
So, "On my way home from school..."
"I saw my father commit adultery
at the castle on top of the mountain..."
And then an... an egg?
"Told me never to speak again. And so..."
The me who never speaks was born.
I see.
Uh... "This is not fiction, but..."
A true story.
Though I did embellish it a little.
So this castle, do you mean that place?
The love hotel that used to be
on the mountaintop?
Right. Pretty mind-blowing.
And I mean in a messed-up way.
Anyway, me peeking into your heart.
You've got the wrong idea, okay?
That egg song the other day.
I was just randomly singing out a story
I heard from some old guy here.
Look, don't you think
it's unproductive to do this by text?
- Besides–
- Stomachache!
What?
Are you okay?
When I talk,
I get a stomachache.
I think that must be the curse.
I see.
Are you sure you’re okay?
I think that must be the curse.
Thank you very much.
I feel a lot better now.
Is that right?
Okay, I'm gonna head home now.
You be care–
What you said today,
do you really believe that?
Do you think you can convey
your feelings better through song?
Are you talking about...
You're asking if it's better?
Well, singing, or music...
I think by nature,
it was always meant to convey something.
So Naruse, if there's something
you want to say...
don't you think you should try singing?
Maybe singing
doesn't count for the curse.
Hey!
What's up with that?
My stomach's starting to hurt again.
I'm going home.
Been a long day.
See you tomorrow.
Oh, is it Naruse?
Yes. The lights are on inside, but...
Oh, but remember, the daughter here.
So Naruse, if there's something
you want to say...
Let me offer them to the eggs
Beautiful words
These words
Let me offer them
My stomach doesn't even hurt!
I know morning practice is optional, but still...
What's with this joke of a turnout?
My bad, Dai.
It must be because I'm such a pushover.
When did I ever say that?
- But–
- You're...
You're doing a great job as captain.
Dai.
Here are our options.
Recitation.
Interpretive dance.
Japanese folk songs and dance.
Chorus.
A cappella choir.
A play.
A play in English.
And just for the heck of it,
as an original act...
a musical.
These are the choices we've come up with.
So let's pick one of these and–
Out of these?
- What a drag.
- What did they do last year, again?
Musical? You mean like
the one we saw yesterday?
Isn't that setting the bar too high?
I don't care what we do,
as long as it's easy.
You got that right!
Now, now.
I don't think it's half bad, this idea.
Rising to the challenge of something new.
That's an awesome feat!
- Not to mention, something new would look
darned good on your school record.
- Not half bad? It was his idea!
Are you people morons or what?
What do you mean, challenge?
You know it's never gonna happen!
You don't have to say it's impossible
before we even get started!
But it is impossible!
In the first place,
what are we gonna do about that girl?
With a girl who can't even talk
on the committee.
Singing, doing a musical.
You've got to be kidding!
Right?
Hey, Tasaki!
What's with all the taunting?
But it's the truth.
Hey, Shimaccho!
Shouldn't we just get rid of that useless kid
and pick a new committee?
- Tasaki! That's enough.
- Who are you to call her useless?
You're the same wherever you go.
Sakagami.
- I feel sorry for the younger guys
on your team.
- Hey, Dai!
What are you talking about?
The younger guys were complaining about you.
"That useless piece of junk!"
Swaggering at practice every single day,
you're a real thorn in their side!
Hey, Sakagami!
You bastard. You're so full of it!
Ikkun?
Shooting off your mouth like that
when you don't know a thing.
What do you know about Dai, anyway?
- Mishima! Calm down!
- Can't breathe...
Hey, cut it out!
What's your problem?
Let me go!
No, I don't think that would be wise.
- Hey! Sakagami!
- I said cut it out!
- Come on!
- You did you just...
I can handle it!
Although I have anxieties,
I'm sure... that... I can...
Naruse? Wait!
Naruse!
What was that?
- Wow.
- That was Naruse?
- Was that a musical?
- Out of nowhere!
Mishima.
Sorry. I kinda lost it.
No...
I was out of line, too.
Hey, are you sure you're okay?
Shouldn't I get the teacher?
Nito, are you in there?
Is Naruse with you?
- Is everything–
- Sakagami.
Where's Naruse?
Inside.
She's locked herself in a stall.
Is this from...?
Naruse?
Yesterday, we just happened to–
Sorry I went ahead
and said all that.
No, I'm sorry. I owe you one.
Does your stomach hurt?
- Does your stomach hurt?
- No, it doesn't hurt.
- It's not hurting me.
- Does your stomach hurt?
- No, it doesn't hurt.
- It's not hurting me.
- Just like you said, Sakagami,
when I sing, it doesn't hurt.
I see. So that's what happened yesterday.
That's why–
But thank goodness
she came back to class after that!
Well, although things were
pretty awkward in that classroom.
Well, yes.
Okay, I'm gonna have lunch in my clubhouse.
Okay.
Naruse had a beautiful voice, huh?
I kind of get
where she's coming from.
There are things that I
can't say either, even if I want to.
Right.
...can handle it!
That song Naruse sang today.
I recreated it.
Why?
After hearing Naruse,
it clicked, right?
Right. That musical-ish DTM
could work, too.
It might even be cool to set
manga dialogue to music, huh?
Hey, sounds good!
Hunter! Let's do Hunter!
- Kinda cliché, don't you think?
- Not really!
Dai!
Hey.
Dai... You coming to practice today?
Sorry.
I have something to take care of.
If what Sakagami said got to you.
That was nothing but–
That's not it.
I really do have an errand to run.
I already let Coach know.
Is that right? Then–
Ikkun!
I'll be waiting for you after practice
at the convenience store again!
- Yoko, come on!
- Right!
Hey, don't be jealous!
Who, me?
See ya.
Hey, you think Sakagami
was showing off for Natsuki today?
Well...
I went to the same junior high with them.
Back then...
- I'm starving!
-Let's stop by the convenience store!
Oh, man, miso potatoes!
Oh, no! It's already here!
Why didn't you get on?
What about you?
In a place like this.
If I get home too early,
my mom will freak out.
When I'm not playing baseball,
it's like time has stopped.
Hey...
If you're free, hang out with me.
Wanna go to that castle
on the mountain with me?
Castle?
But that's a love hotel!
As if I'd go there!
Anyway, it went out of business last year...
You sure know a lot about it.
That's because I heard everyone
talking about it!
Go out with me.
I told you...
I can't. I'm seeing someone else.
Who?
That's a secret.
Then how long were you with Sakagami?
Did you go to that castle with him?
We've never even held hands.
Actually...
I don't even know his email address.
And you call that dating?
What does it matter?
Where are you going?
The bus.
The next train won't come for over 30 minutes.
If you want to kill time, then help us
with the Community Outreach event.
It looks like we'll have
our work cut out for us.
You can kill lots of time.
Dammit...
Oh, is it Naruse again?
Yeah, what should I do?
Should I tell the chairman...
Well, well!
Right, duly paid!
Confirming receipt of this month's
block association dues.
Your mother's always late
getting home, isn't she?
Isn't this a rough time
for the insurance industry?
With so few people buying policies.
Oh, by the way...
How's school, Jun?
My kid's taking the entrance exams
next year, you know?
And I was wondering
about your school, Jun.
Good evening.
Uh...
Welcome home!
You see, I came for the
block association dues.
I'm sorry.
I've been so busy lately.
I've already collected them.
See you, Jun!
Good night, then.
Thank you for your hard work.
Don't answer the door if I'm not here.
It's disgraceful.
A child who doesn't speak. There are
rumors all over the place. Really, now...
Oh, the car.
Jun!
Hey, where are you going?
Let's see. Light bulbs, yogurt...
All right.
If she sings, huh?
What's this?
It's super-long!
Another one?
Um...
Hold up a second!
Uh... What's going on here?
Please turn my words into song.
Words, into song?
I don't get it.
Excuse me!
Excuse me.
I want you to do what you did
with that egg song!
Naruse?
My feelings...
What I really want to say!
Into a beautiful...
song...
Hey!
Naruse!
Hey...
Where's Takumi?
Out shopping.
I asked him to go get some light bulbs.
The one in the bathroom went out.
At this hour?
Stop asking Takumi to do everything!
I was in the middle of something–
Come on.
It's this way.
Watch your step, okay?
Takumi?
Hey...
Forget the pleasantries!
It's at the end of the hall there.
Is that a friend?
I guess?
Hey! The light bulb!
In the bathroom!
Hold up a sec!
The young girl who likes daydreaming
yearns to attend the nightly ball at the castle.
But this ball...
was actually an execution site for criminals.
They are condemned to atone for their sins...
by dancing forever, until they die.
Such a curse has been cast upon them.
Despite knowing the truth,
the young girl, still wanting to go to the ball,
begins to commit all kinds of crimes.
However...
nobody ever charges her with those crimes.
There, a mysterious egg appears
and incites the girl in despair.
Telling her,
"The most egregious sin in this world...
is to hurt others with your words."
The girl begins spouting
every abusive word she can think of...
hurting others...
earning their dislike...
and the next thing she knows...
She's lost the ability to speak.
I wrote it based on
what had happened to myself.
This is kind of disturbing, you know.
So what happens in the end?
This is all I have so far,
and I haven't come up with the ending yet.
What she really wants to say, huh?
Good evening!
Please help yourself, if you like!
I hear you're Ms. Naruse's daughter!
My, but you do have the same exact eyes!
Well, girls are–
Grams, is it all right if we
use the room upstairs?
What? Yes...
Well, of course you can.
This is my dad's room.
His hobby is music.
So even though I didn't want to,
he made me learn how to play the piano.
You can sit here.
Grams, huh?
There are a bunch of show tunes in here, see.
Like what I did with that egg song.
I can't write songs from scratch, so...
we can just stick some lyrics
into existing songs.
For example...
this part from that email you just sent me.
Let's see.
At the glittering golden castle
Night after night, it happens
Attended by gentlemen and ladies
That ball
Something like that.
That's overkill!
The lyrics are yours, remember?
My bad.
The thing about you, Naruse...
Even if you don't sing, you display exactly
what you’re thinking.
See?
That's what I'm talking about!
Hey...
Are you sure you don't need to get picked up?
I see.
We should talk to Nito
about this tomorrow.
That we want to put on a musical
for the Community Outreach event.
So be sure to finish that story, okay?
Turn what you really want to say into a story.
Now?
Yeah.
You can come after practice, of course.
Since we can't use the gym today,
we should be done early...
Then we'll be waiting for you at the diner.
Text me if you're running late.
See you.
I don't even know your email address!
Killing time at the station again today?
Sarcastic, much?
If that's the case...
Were you nervous there?
Before we head to the diner,
I want to stop by somewhere.
What the hell, man?
I thought you had no interest in 3D!
Voice actors are 2.5D!
This is it.
What are you doing?
DTM Research Club
Jeez, if you’re bringing a girl here,
let us know in advance!
What's up with that?
Sorry, Naruse!
For doing this without telling you.
Does that mean you don't mind?
Thank God.
Listen,
what if I was serious about doing
a musical for the Community Outreach event?
A pain in the ass.
I totally don't like the idea.
But if you're serious, I'm in.
I do want to hear
Naruse sing some more.
Is that a confession of love?
Of course it's not!
- Jeez...
- My harem's already full!
There's no room for
a 3D girl to squeeze in!
Gotcha. Your harem?
We've already got one song.
Within the time frame,
the most we can fit in is six songs?
And then–
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Oh, he looked totally available, so...
Tasaki is on the committee, after all.
So what did you want to talk about?
Oh, the thing is...
Uh, is this...
A story that Naruse wrote.
Naruse wrote it?
We wanted to tell you...
we want to adapt this story
into a musical for the Outreach event.
So we're putting on an original work.
But this story...
Oh, the ending isn't done yet.
But are you okay?
With putting on a musical?
Yeah...
After seeing Naruse yesterday.
I see. And Tasaki?
Naruse...
Uh... You know...
About yesterday–
Ditching practice is a piece of cake
without Tasaki around!
Yeah, seriously.
I wish he'd stop coming for good!
Four drink bar, please.
The second years are all slacking off.
Cups are over there.
There's no point. Right, Yamaji?
Yeah.
Okay. Can we have one menu?
Mishima's pretty ineffectual.
What's gonna happen to our team?
Shall we get potatoes? Potatoes!!
What?
T-Tasaki...
What do you think you're doing?
Sorry!
Who asked you to apologize?
Apologizing to me won't cut it.
Not even realizing
what Mishima's going through.
What the hell do you think you're doing?
Right back at you.
Yamaji! Knock it off!
What are you doing?
Not showing up at practice,
taking some girl out...
You're wrong about that!
We're here to discuss
the Community Outreach event...
Outreach?
Just spit it out, Yamaji.
When the new team
hasn't even gelled yet,
you really are laid-back.
What do you mean, "You're our ace now?"
All you ever do is throw your weight around!
You're an eyesore!
I wish you disappeared
from my sight!
Cut it...
Cut it out!
Don't tell people to disappear
like it's nothing!
Words can hurt people!
You can't ever...
You can't ever take them back!
Even if you regret,
you can never take them back!
Naruse?
Are you okay?
About what?
About...
That egg curse...
Naruse, are you all right?
- Is she okay?
- A doctor! No, an ambulance!
What do we do?
Phone! Cell phone!
- Was it 114? Or 116?
- Excuse me, you're
disturbing the other customers.
- Never mind, just dial!
- Excuse me, you're
disturbing the other customers.
Sorry, it's an emergency!
Shimonita Hospital
Jun!
I get a call from the hospital
and rush over, only to find...
What do you mean, a stomachache?
Is this that curse thing again?
Excuse me...
This can't get any worse.
Okay, you're all set.
Please take care.
- Thank you very much.
- Oh, no! I've got to get going.
OK. Let's tell Naruse–
Listen.
My bad.
It wasn't your fault–
No, I–
Why do you do this?
Do you hate me that much?
Never saying a word!
The neighbors always gossip about you.
What are you trying to do?
Are you doing this to spite me?
Say something, will you?
Be rebellious if you want to.
I don't understand.
I... I'm so tired!
Of my job. Of the way you are. All of it!
You're Sakagami's...
Uh... Naruse - Jun - is a cheerful kid.
She's not a chatterbox,
but... well...
She talks a lot inside her soul!
The reason she got sick today...
was because she pushed herself
too hard for our friend. So...
I don't know...
I know I keep saying I don't know, but...
I just want to say that
Naruse is always really...
She's doing her best!
You know, I was pretty surprised.
About what?
About all kinds of things.
Hey, are you sure you're okay
with doing a musical?
I think I understand
how Naruse feels, too, so...
Because there were things
I wanted to say and couldn't, either.
Back in junior high,
when you were going through
the hardest time of your life,
I couldn't do anything for you.
Even though I was your girlfriend.
Even so...
Are Natsuki and Sakagami going out?
N-No...!
What Naruse said back there.
That words can hurt.
That really hit home.
That was typical
junior high kid behavior.
I'm such a boring guy.
I was never a good match for you.
That's not true!
You never whine, no matter what,
you're so considerate.
You always notice
when someone's in trouble.
And also...
Thanks.
You're welcome.
No, but...
I was okay with being a boring guy, you know.
It was tiring to express my feelings
or argue back to someone.
Clashing with others was a pain,
so I was like, whatever.
But Naruse...
Even though she was suffering,
she tried so hard to somehow express
the words inside her head.
When I saw that, I thought I...
What am I saying?
Well, I guess I mean that
I want to cheer her on!
Sakagami, you have feelings for...
What's wrong?
I'm going to cheer her on,
and you too, Sakagami!
Why me?
Because you've stirred up
the cheerleader in me!
What's that about?
- Being able to talk to Nito like this again...
- Boy, I'm starved! Let's get going!
- I have Naruse to thank for that, too.
- We're gonna be really busy starting tomorrow.
You think so?
So you do have friends.
The block association dues.
Thanks for that.
Naruse is always really... She's doing her best!
The prince bestowed upon the young girl,
who'd filled herself with sorrowful words,
extremely precious words of bliss,
like water seeping into the desert.
I missed out on my chance to apologize.
- What's wrong?
- He glared at me something fierce!
- What? Maybe he's into you, Aki!
- That would be terrifying!
Jeez...
The guy who routinely ditches
morning practice finally shows up,
and this happens.
Sorry.
The others are already in the gym. Hurry over.
Right.
Huh? Dai!
We have practice in the gym...
I'm sorry about everything till now!
Wha–
- The game, my injury... that's all on me.
- Hold up, Dai!
- It's not all on you...
- I know.
But the thing is, I've got to do this
or we'll never get anywhere.
Even though I'm such a bonehead,
I was thinking
I was the only one carrying the load.
Bossing you all around,
saying it's for the sake of the team.
But the truth is, I was shoving it all on you,
Yamaji, and the other guys as much as I could.
But that's because I'm not a good captain.
That's not true.
It's not about that.
If I keep this up,
everything about me is half-baked.
Even though you guys are clenching
your teeth and taking it.
I know it's selfish of me to just apologize
and be the one without a burden!
But can't you let me
start over right here, right now?
Yamaji...
Start over how?
Get healed up and shoot for the Nationals
again with you guys.
- I'm going to practice.
- Yamaji!
So what are you gonna do now?
I'm gonna start by dealing with
everything I can now, one by one.
I see.
Really, I'm overcome with joy!
If you yearn so much to put on a musical,
then I'll throw my full support!
Like it wasn't your idea.
Now if Tasaki would show up,
we'll all be here.
We've got nothing to fear!
That's one thing
that's probably not gonna happen.
What are you talking about?
No matter the time or place, when it comes
to musicals, a miracle always seems to happen.
I wouldn't bet on–
Excuse me.
Hey, what's this?
Naruse...
Sorry I trashed you the other day!
If you don't mind,
let me help make this thing happen.
Is that a no?
T-Tasaki.
Of course! Thank you very much!
I'm looking forward to working with you, too.
What's going on?
See? It did happen, right? A miracle!
So anyway, at this year's Outreach event...
we're going to put on
a musical based on that handout.
What's up with that?
Why so sudden?
Isn't that a bit much?
You were against this
more than anyone!
I know, right?
That's right.
I totally blasted Naruse,
saying we could never pull off a musical.
But Naruse proved that we could, didn't she?
So we're gonna do it.
But that's just your own personal issue, Tasaki.
I wish you wouldn't drag us into it.
Wait...
Why musical anyway?
It's the most complex option.
And this is an original work, right?
We've only got a month and a bit
before the Outreach event.
And only a handful of people from
the neighborhood show up.
Right. That's why we should
do something simpler.
True...
At first, I didn't really care either,
to be honest.
But...
If even one of us is ready to go all-in,
it'd be cool to ride on their coattails
and pull out all the stops to get it done.
Me, too. We don't have much time,
and it might be a lot of work,
but as committee members,
we'll do everything we can!
So why not?
If we do something,
the more extravagant, the better!
Besides, this looks kind of interesting!
I agree. There are dance numbers
in musicals, right?
I've been wanting to try
my hand at choreography.
Edacchi...
Taku! You're gonna let us
handle the songs, right?
This will be the DTM Club's day in the sun.
Needless to say, I'll give you a hand
with the music-related stuff.
We do have a bit of funding, after all...
You mean we can go hardcore
with the artwork?
The costumes, too?
Well, I did say "a bit of..."
Well, if we have to do something anyway.
- Singing and dancing?
- I can be a stagehand, right?
But I've got cram school.
- And I have my part-time job.
- Hey, it's all good!
I've got practice, too,
so I won't be much help,
but if we each do as much as we can.
Right, committee member?
Of course!
Um, after hearing your feedback, of course,
we'd like to allocate all the roles.
- Well, in that case...
- Yeah.
Well, not like there's anything else I want to do.
Hey, what about casting?
Looks like the only really
demanding role is the heroine.
Well, that's another thing we'll be...
Isn't Naruse going to play the heroine?
You're not?
All right, then it's settled.
The prince appears before the girl
who'd lost the ability to speak.
Because of her encounter with the prince,
words of love begin to proliferate
inside the girl's heart.
But the girl...
is unable to voice them.
One day, an assassination attempt
is made on the prince,
and thanks to a ruse by the Egg,
the girl is charged with the crime.
Because she can't speak,
she fails to clear up the misunderstanding,
and is captured by all the people
she'd hurt till then and is sentenced to death.
As the prince looks on,
the girl's head is chopped off on the scaffold.
That's when the words begin to gush out
of the girl's head...
"I love the prince."
I don't know, it's pretty gory.
But I don't think it's bad for an ending!
You don't?
After the girl dies,
everyone realizes the truth, right?
It clears things up with the prince.
Isn't Gon, the Little Fox like that, too?
It's got that fairy-tale vibe.
Well, I guess it's better than
a random happy ending.
Yeah. I think it works.
Still, the prince is such a crucial role.
And I'm the one who has to play him?
At least you're a human!
I'm an egg. An egg!
Not that it's your fault, Naruse.
What's wrong with that?
I bet you'll look cute!
Lucky you. You're in the chorus
and one of the criminals, right?
What choice do we have? We told them we'd do
everything we could as committee members.
And of course, all the main characters
were forced upon the committee members.
Girl/Jun Naruse
Egg/Daiki Tasaki
Prince/Takumi Sakagami
An egg. An egg...
Just resign yourself already.
But!
Naruse, you just need to write
the lyrics for the ending, right?
Do you think you'll be able to say
what you really want to say?
I see.
The wind feels cold now.
Yeah, it might be torture for us
to go on eating up here.
The words she'd lost start to shout out...
Start to shout out
"I love you."
By the way, does this
have a title yet?
Yeah, I think it's The Shin of Youth.
That's so lame!
It has nothing to do with the story!
Coming! Oh, my, welcome!
Are you here for Taku?
Yes.
Come on in!
Taku, your friend is here!
Excuse me!
Oh, my, what a spirited young man!
S-Sorry...
- Hey, you're early.
- It's okay.
If it's a 3 o'clock call time,
showing up at 2:50 is a no-brainer.
Hey, you can leave that open.
This place is more or less soundproof.
Right. Pretty amazing.
Well, at least in number.
We can use them to decide
the last number we haven't–
Hey, I don't know much about music,
so I'm counting on you for that.
Anyway, where are the others?
Aizawa and Iwaki should be
here any minute.
Nito and Naruse will come after
they're done shopping for the costume people.
By the way, I hear
you and Nito used to go out.
What? How did–
Uh, that was back when
we were in junior high.
We were briefly an item–
Well, Nito's apparently seeing
someone else now.
Of course she has someone.
Not that I know anything about it.
- Let's play, Takumi!
- Hey, they're here.
Sorry, can you help me
move the sofa?
Taku, your friends are here!
Everybody must be there already by now.
Shall we get a move on?
Let's see, on the map.
Naruse, have you been to
Sakagami's house before?
I see.
Just once, when we were thinking up the story.
He set music to my words with the piano.
Sakagami played the piano?
It feels so strange.
Going over to a friend's house, going shopping with a friend.
It never really seemed
possible till now...
Friend...
I'm sorry!
Having the nerve to call you my friend when we're only on the Outreach committee together...!
No, that's not it!
I'm glad that we
got to be friends, too!
You totally make me want to cheer you on.
My heart
just won't shout it out
I can't help but feel
that there was something
I wanted to say
...Like this?
Hey, not bad.
I think it matches
the melancholy of the ending.
When Iwaki said classical music,
I wasn't sure what we were gonna do!
Works for me, this Misery.
Pathétique!
Not much difference.
Oh yes, they are different!
- Apologize to Master Beethoven!
- Okay...
Now we've got all the songs
picked out, right?
All right! Now for the arrangements!
We might need to tweak the lyrics, too.
Also, the choreography and direction!
In any case, just one more push!
Boy, that took up a lot of time, huh?
True that. Having so much material
is pretty daunting, huh?
Yeah, but this room really gets me fired up!
So sorry to make you help me!
Oh, those sweets?
Put them in that bowl, will you?
They're quite good, you know.
Tell me, the song we just heard...
That was Takkun playing, wasn't it?
Is that right?
That song. My son loved it.
Since Takkun was such a good pianist,
the whole family used to gather
in that room and listen to him play...
Jun?
Oh, my. What is it?
Let's see...
What are you doing?
Oh! Takkun.
What does this say?
What happened to Sakagami's parents?
My parents are divorced, too.
My mom who left us, and...
After that, my dad's been busy
with work or whatever...
and left me in my grandparents' care.
Well, I guess we see each other
once a year, at most.
Taku?
Can I help?
No, we're good.
We'll be right there.
All right, then. Thanks for having us!
See you around, Taku!
See you at school!
Take care, all right?
Hey, let's stop by the book store.
We're taking the bus to the station, right?
Shall we go?
Are you sure you didn't need
to take that train?
What's up?
The doctor told me
I still shouldn't be running,
so I'm trying to walk as much as I can.
Wait, you don't want
to walk with me?
Still, that was pretty awesome, huh?
Both Aizawa and Iwaki
really know their music.
And Sakagami looked so cool,
playing the piano.
The people in our class
all have their talents and skills.
So do you, Naruse.
Well, I guess I wasn't paying
any attention till now.
What is it?
That's so admirable of you.
To realize that yourself.
Jeez! You talking to a kid?
Come on, let's go.
I'm the one who never paid any attention.
The young girl had received
such precious, blissful words...
But she wasn't aware of the prince's grief.
What kind of words
could the girl utter to the prince?
You want to change the ending?
But Naruse...
This is the new ending.
- Just before execution,
- All right, fairies! Let's try it together now!
- just when she'd given up all hope,
- The prince rushes to protect her.
- Let's look at the lyrics for now.
- At the prince's urging, the people ended up forgiving her.
The girl, the prince, and everyone else as well
all get a happy ending...
I just thought that the elderly
would enjoy a happy ending more...
So, change the current ending and add one more song?
We don't have much time, so cut the
sad last song, and just act out?
I see. I did like the lyrics
we've got now, you know.
Sure, they're gloomy, but...
The part where she shouts out, "I love you."
It felt that her repressed feelings
were really precious to her.
That's what it felt like to me.
But I agree, a happy ending
would appeal more to the masses!
Stop! Stop!
What's the problem, Aizawa?
Did we mess up somewhere?
No, that's not it.
Then what's wrong?
Aizawa?
It's just...!
This song is about us evil fairies
deceiving the girl,
burning down the town,
and massacring the people, right?
So is it really okay for us
to sing it so merrily?
Well, what are we supposed to do?
We're ones doing the deceiving,
so of course we're happy!
Mismatched lyrics and music.
Happens all the time!
It's that dissonance that makes it riveting,
don't you think?
Sorry about this, Naruse.
Something just hit me, see.
About that last song...
Oh, hey, I'm all for the happy ending!
But when I started thinking how great
the atmosphere of the original ending was.
Let's see...
Happy...
The song we heard the other day in class.
It actually fits pretty well, I guess.
In this musical I saw years ago,
there was a number where they sang
two different songs at once.
And I remembered how amazing it was,
listening to Aizawa and the others talking.
I learned this one from my dad, too.
I left you hanging yesterday, didn't I?
My parents were already fighting all the time
before I got into junior high...
My mom wanted me
to get into a private school,
but I was so hooked on the piano
at the time, and I rebelled.
And my dad defended me.
I ended up going to a public school,
but the discord between
my parents only got worse.
And what happened next
was what I told you yesterday.
Even though my own selfishness
was the cause,
I couldn't do anything.
I couldn't say a word.
Since I blamed myself,
I got scared to even touch the piano.
There's no way that it was your fault!
Then the same goes for
what happened to your family.
I can't believe that it was your fault.
That's probably just how it is.
That's not true that something or somebody
being 100% to blame or wrong.
Anyway, what I wanted
to suggest was,
if both of these endings are
what you really want to say,
why don't we somehow
convey both of them?
Just a thought I had.
Sakagami, you're amazing.
No...
You're amazing.
Would you mind playing it again?
I want to listen well and will put everything I want to convey in that song.
I want to cram it all in.
My
prince!
Music Room
Community Outreach Event
Arts/Sports-related
The Shin of Youth
Girl/Jun Naruse
Egg/Daiki Tasaki
Prince/Takumi Sakagami
Please come see this, if you want.
Morning!
We're going on for real tomorrow!
And I'm still not sure about the lyrics...
Same here. I'm still worried
about the choreography.
I know, right?
Morning, Sakagami!
Morning.
You're here early.
Sure am!
Hey, Nito. About getting permission
to use the gym this after–
Oh, right!
Sorry! I'll take care of it right away!
Hey! Natsuki?
- No. I was going to join you.
- Wait up, will you?
OK!
We're done with rehearsals for all parts!
All right, it's getting late,
so clear up and get out of here!
What?
Don't "what?" me.
Tomorrow, the first years
will be using the stage first,
so make sure you do a good job clearing up!
Okay, let's get to it.
Then let's start with the big stuff...
Hey!
I brought in the troops for the heavy lifting!
Ikkun!
It's the baseball team!
All right!
Those guys.
Where should we take this?
- That's fragile, so be careful, okay?
- Hey, could you give us a hand?
All right. Hey.
I'll take that.
Hey, thanks.
Not at all.
But is your elbow okay?
The doctor finally cleared me.
I could start practicing next week.
Wait for me just a little longer.
Right.
Hey, Natsuki?
If you're heading back to the classroom,
could you take this, too?
Oh, hold up a second.
Then can you go, too, Sakagami?
Hey, Nito.
Aren't you acting
a little weird lately?
Like how?
Like how? You know...
It's nothing, all right?
What is it?
Really, Ikkun, you're such a bad boy!
Well, what can I do?
Lately we've been so busy prepping for this,
we could never be alone.
But in a place like this...
How could they
when it's crunch time for us?
I don't care if they're dating.
Doing that stuff at school.
Dating.
Well... You're dating
someone now, right?
How'd you know?
I heard about it the other day from Tasaki.
Nito?
Nito!
Stay away from me!
Wait, you...
You're crying.
Look, Nito...
Forget it!
Just forget it.
I'll take care of the rest.
Put that down, and...
Go be with Naruse!
Why would you bring her up now?
Because you're in love, aren't you?
With Naruse?
Hold up! Where'd you get that idea?
It's not like I'm in love with Naruse!
But, you're always concerned about her!
I mean really!
That's right, I am concerned!
But that's because... I don't know.
Didn't I tell you before?
Naruse's been trying so hard.
So I want to cheer her on!
Isn't that what being in love is?
I'm telling you, you're wrong!
Why are you making assumptions
about other people's feelings?
I can't tell!
I can't tell what you're feeling at all!
Yeah... guess not.
You can't tell what I'm thinking.
I've got to put them into words.
I always regretted it.
That day, when you tried
to reach out to me...
I knew you were,
but I didn't do anything about it.
That's why...
Seeing Naruse trying so hard...
I... I thought, "This time I'll–
As for me, after that,
things between us got so vague...
But I was glad it ended up that way.
If I asked you. If I said it out loud,
I thought it would really be over
between us. All this time...
Does that mean...
Then the guy you're seeing...
But that's not how I should've handled it.
And now that I know that I handled it wrong,
That's why I said I'd cheer you on.
Nito, I–
We should get going.
Everyone's waiting.
Nito...
Sorry. I don't want to hear it now.
But...
It made me happy
to hear you play the piano again.
What's wrong?
These are the bags
I asked Naruse to bring.
Where's Naruse?
Seems like it's something urgent?
Ow...
It hurts... it hurts... it hurts!
It's not your stomach, I see.
It's your heart that hurts.
It's the pain of youth.
Inflicted on you for breaking the seal...
I haven't spoken! Hardly at all!
When you're told not to speak,
it's not just about words.
You have a heart that talks too much.
Takumi Sakagami...
I love him I love him I love him I love him
I love him I love him I love him...
Stop it!
So you see?
Your egg is full of cracks now.
Aha, here it comes.
The slimy egg whites.
The about-to-be-hatched yolk...
I'm very disappointed in you.
Let's bring this superficial
imprisonment to an end.
All right, it's time for...
Some scrambled eggs.
To think it would snow at this time of year!
Community Outreach Event
Hey!
Has anyone found Naruse yet?
No. And we haven't heard
from anyone else, either.
There's nowhere else to look
on the school grounds!
Not hearing back from the guys
patrolling outside, either.
Is she really at school?
Well, her shoes were in her locker!
Sakagami, what about her cell phone?
No good. I can't get through.
And her voicemail's–
Sorry. I can't play the heroine. I
was carried away. Really sorry.
Why?
She can't play the heroine?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Why so suddenly?
It's no good. I can't call her.
What are we gonna do?
Without our heroine, we've got nothing!
You think this has something to do with
Naruse's urgent business yesterday?
Hey! When you two went back
to the classroom yesterday,
did you run into Naruse?
Yesterday...
You took stuff back
to the classroom, right?
It was around that time when
Naruse went to pick up some bags.
Around that time?
Then that sound we heard...
Naruse heard what we were saying.
Heard you? Heard you say what? Hey!
Well...
Is Naruse here?
We looked for her off the school gro–
What were you thinking?
At a crucial time like this!
Hey, Dai...
But we don't know if that's
the reason, unless Naruse...
You!
You can't be...
What am I gonna do?
Natsuki...
What, you mean...
That thing you call
the tangles of blind love?
- What's up with that?
- Is that why Naruse's a no-show?
What's that?
Isn't that kind of outrageous?
After we all worked so hard to get ready.
That's kind of a jerk move
by Naruse, don't you think?
Hey!
What are you gonna do?
I...
Hm, nobody's picking up
at Naruse's house either.
What is it?
Well, it's just that...
You guys, I'm sorry!
No need for you to apologize, Taku...
The idea was ours, and with
your cooperation, we made it this far.
And yet, Naruse is about to destroy it all.
And I think that's a truly heinous betrayal.
But I...
Even so...
She was so frantic. Even though
her stomach hurts her when she talks,
she ignored it so she could push on.
And since I saw that...
I want her to get up
on that stage, no matter what!
Well, sure. We know how hard
Naruse was working, too.
But the fact is, she's a no-show.
So I want you to let me go look for her.
What are you saying?
What are we supposed to do
if you leave, too?
Iwaki, it was you who wrote all the songs,
so you can sing them all, right?
Well...
Then until Sakagami gets back,
I want you to play the prince.
Nito?
Since you're the one who directed Naruse,
you know the songs, don't you?
I want you to take Naruse's place.
Me?
You were only going on once anyway,
so you can take this.
And Iwaki, the fairy and the prince
don't come on at the same time, either!
Well, no...
Tasaki...
Let me ask for your cooperation, too!
I just want you to give Naruse
the slightest chance.
Please!
I promise to do my very best, too!
And I'll dance enough
for both Natsuki and me!
Yoko, let's go over the part
where the formation changes again.
Iwaki, if you're not up to it,
I wouldn't mind playing the prince.
You wouldn't fit into the costume, Aizawa!
Hey.
I'm counting on you.
Wait for me, Naruse!
Why, hello. Ms. Naruse!
The first years just finished
their performance now.
If you like, this seat next to us is open!
Hey, Sakagami?
Sorry. Still no sign of Naruse.
Oh, it's not that. Here's a message
from Tasaki who went on ahead.
He says that Naruse's mom
is in the audience.
Gotcha. Thanks!
We'll head over as soon as I find her.
Dammit. What are you doing, Naruse?
The me who never speaks was born.
Come to think of it.
Naruse did mention that day...
It all started with...
The ball at the castle!
They're taking a long time, huh?
At the glittering golden castle...
Hey, I'm starting to get nervous.
Night after night, it happens.
- The place is packed!
- Oh, man, I've got a stomachache!
- Me, too.
Attended by gentlemen and ladies...
Hey, I heard from the teacher in charge of scheduling.
That ball...
He can't delay our start time any longer.
Hey, Nito?
That ball...
What?
What's this? You always dance
in a short skirt as a cheerleader.
Have you lost your nerve?
Maybe.
I'd lost my nerve, probably.
All this time...
I might have been running away
from making things clear.
But I'm done with that!
All right, then let's go!
Right!
Once upon a time, in a certain land...
There lived a poor young girl
who yearned to go to the ball at the castle.
At the glittering golden castle
Night after night, it happens
Attended by gentlemen and ladies
That ball...
Wasn't the main character supposed to be played by someone else?
Her fluttering dress is like a red fish
So she couldn't go through with it, after all...
She swims through the hall, waving her tail...
Hey, Natsuki's really singing out!
Though she does seems a little stiff.
What are you doing here, may I ask?
I also feel so nervous.
I'm counting an you, Sakagami!
Bring Naruse back as soon as you can!
If it's dark, then just a little bit
Let me dream
This way?
Look at the time!
But if I find Naruse...
Even if it's a dark deception
I...
I don't care, I want to dance
Naruse.
Let's go, Naruse.
Everybody's waiting.
I can't go back anymore.
Naruse? You–
It's already started, hasn't it?
No, there's still time!
Because they're somehow getting by for now.
It's hopeless.
I can't sing anymore.
Because my prince doesn't exist anymore.
- Naruse–
- Don't come near me!
Don't make me shout!
My stomach will start hurting again,
don't you see?
Thought I could do it if I sang...
But it didn't work out!
Talking.
My heart talking.
It didn't work, after all!
It was just like the Egg said!
Because I spoke up, I became unhappy!
There was never any egg, and you know it!
Yes, there is!
There isn't!
There is!
Isn't!
I need him to exist, or I'd be lost!
I've ruined the play.
I've ruined my family.
If my being a chatterbox wasn't to blame...
What am I supposed to blame it all on?
What am I supposed to do?
So you're telling me
that you wish to commit a crime?
That's right! I want to dance!
Even knowing that it's a ball for criminals
being held at that castle.
Even so!
The girl makes a desperate appeal.
Well, in that case, you've got to
commit a crime just as grave as theirs!
That's right! For example...
Stick my hand in my pocket
I've got one box of matches
It's not even that cold and you light a fire
What's up with that ad-lib sound effect?
I guess he's too carried away.
Hey, are we good?
Hey! Don't move!
You're going on next, right?
Aizawa is doing his best in his own way.
The wavering flames flicker upward
But you know–
I know you're worried about Naruse,
but we're all doing our best
even with all our misgivings.
A faraway, sweet life
Well, but it's all the same to me
whether she shows up or not.
Dancing, talking, the frills on your dress
I mean we're doing the same thing either way!
The worst outcome would be
to mess up this musical, right?
Romantic games at daybreak
And if that were to happen,
I think Naruse would regret it the most.
Rise up in flames, burn it to the ground
So either way, we've got
to make sure this is a success!
And your true feelings?
After all that practice,
I don't want it to go to waste!
True!
Well, I guess you're right!
It's too late anyway, it's already started!
True! True!
I wish it would just burn up!
Me.
My soul.
All my chattering, too!
- Naru–
- I've got to blame it on my talkativeness.
Or I wouldn't know what to do!
I really don't know what to do!
Jun Naruse!
W-What is it?
You have a sweet voice, you know.
Talk to me some more.
Say what you really want to say.
Give me more of those words.
Didn't you hear what I just said?
Of course that's not gonna happen!
Words...
Words hurt other people!
You can hurt me.
I don't mind if I get hurt.
I want to hear you
speak the truth some more.
Naruse!
Okay, then, I'm gonna start hurting you now.
You pretend to be kind,
but you're such a hypocrite!
Your armpits smell sometimes!
You're not even that good-looking!
Just because you can play the piano,
don't be deluded that you're popular!
You liar!
You're always leading people on.
You pretentious bastard!
Also!
That girl! That girl is equally to blame!
She's a liar! And she's a goody-two-shoes!
That's the most vile kind of person there is!
Also...
Also?
I've run out of things to say.
Really?
I've run out!
Is that all? All your words of truth?
Name!
Just now, you said my name.
I've never said your name before.
Say it.
Takumi Sakagami.
Takumi Sakagami!
What? I wonder why?
I was just like you, Naruse.
I'd talk, but...
I fell into the habit of not saying
what I really felt, somewhere along the way.
And then, I started believing
that there wasn't anything...
that I really wanted to tell anyone.
But then I met you.
You don't usually talk,
but you do have so many things
you want to convey.
And I started to realize that
maybe there were many things
I wanted to tell someone
and I wanted to talk about.
I'm glad that I met you!
Thanks to you, I think
I realized all kinds of things!
This is all...
Thanks to me?
Not my fault?
That's right!
So there isn't any egg after all!
Because whatever he told you
was a pack of lies!
Because your words made me happy!
So–
Me, too. It's all thanks to you, Sakagami.
It's thanks to you, to Nito,
to Tasaki, to everyone!
But I...
Let's go.
They're all waiting.
For you.
They're waiting!
I have one more thing that I want to say.
I love you, Sakagami!
Thanks.
But I'm in love with someone else.
I knew that.
The girl begins spouting
every abusive word she can think of.
Hurting others. Earning their dislike.
Let's stay and watch a little longer.
Right. Jun and Takkun
worked so hard to prepare this.
The next thing she knows,
she'd lost the ability to speak.
So you've lost the ability to speak!
That's your punishment for your crimes!
That's what everyone wants,
for you to lose your voice!
No. I never wanted that.
Farewell, my voice...
Beyond that mountain,
into the lake sleeping so deeply
Now it is gone
Look, Tasaki!
The sorrowful words that scar people's hearts
Your cell phone just lit up!
It's from Sakagami!
Gimme that!
Did he find Naruse?
But now what are we gonna do?
Taku's on his way here with Naruse!
Not wanting to utter them, it sobbed...
Switching with Nito now?
But we're already past the halfway point.
The only scenes left are...
But this is perfect.
Now it is gone
What's so perfect?
The Voice of the Girl's Soul is coming up, right?
Where we leave the girl who can't talk onstage,
Good morning, hello, how are you today?
and have Nito and the others sing backstage.
She can just appear singing that.
The voice of her soul is going to appear?
But then we'll have two girls onstage!
It's all good.
Those ordinary conversations
After all, musicals and miracles
go hand in hand, right?
How I miss them now
My voice disappeared, much to everyone's jay
Because everyone hates the wards that I say
Heaving with sobs, my voice left me and is gone
Left behind, I can no longer even cry
And so, the girl who'd lost her voice
finally collapsed under the weight of her crimes.
The girl is in despair.
But just then, a prince passes by.
Naruse!
You were great, Naruse!
Yeah, your entrance was so dramatic.
- It was really cool!
- That was a little nerve-wracking.
We were worried.
Naruse! Get your makeup on...
Hey, no crying!
I won't be able to get you made up!
Naruse, you're on again right after this.
We're counting on you till the end!
I...
- I caused you all so much trouble.
- She's talking?
And still...
Come on, we told you not to cry!
You're seeing this through, aren't you?
Inside the egg are...
Is your stomach okay?
Egg whites gone cold and an ominous yolk
So there never really was an egg.
I'm the one who cast that curse.
I was the egg.
Locked away inside the egg, alone. Me, myself.
Just then, the world burst
into song towards the girl.
This is it, huh? Go on!
Now, then...
I will call out your name
My heart begins to shout
I will call out your gentle name
The world I see standing next to you
You taught me to see
Everything is so beautiful
This beautiful world
My sad past as well as the traces of my tears
I will embrace this world
I'm going to shout out
I will embrace the whole everything
The feelings that were born since I met you
I love you
I love everything about it
I love you so much
This world that you gave me
Community Outreach Event
So listen,
I'm gonna go confess my feelings to Naruse.
I'm starting practice again
after the weekend, you know?
So I won't have much spare time...
That's why you're doing it now?
So, can I step away for a second?
We still have some cleaning up to do,
so make sure you come back.
Okay, I'm going now!
Pretty amazing, huh? That Tasaki.
Nito?
Listen...
The rest of that conversation
you said you didn't want to hear.
Can I talk now?
No.
Right now, it's like you're
piggybacking onto Tasaki, so no.
No, that's not–
Another time!
Tell me properly.
And I'll give you a proper answer.
Come on! Let's get back to work!
What's inside the egg?
All kinds of feelings locked inside.
Then, unable to keep them locked in...
It explodes...
And the world that's created then...
It is more beautiful than I ever thought.